I Lombard General Insurance company
limiteds Q2 and H1 fy4 earnings
conference call from the Senior
Management we have with us today Mr
barav Das Gupta MD and CEO of the
company Mr gopal balachandran CFO and
cro Mr sanjie mantri executive director
and Mr alok Agarwal executive
director please note that any statements
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involves risk and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being
expressed as a reminder all participant
lines will be in the listen only mode
and there will be an opportunity for you
to ask questions after the presentation
concludes should you need assistance
during the conference call please signal
an operator by pressing star 10 on a
touchstone
phone I now hand the conference over to
Mr bav Das Gupta MD and CEO ICI Lombard
General Insurance Limited thank you I
know to you sir thank you ziko and good
evening to each one of you thank you for
joining the earnings conference call of
I Lumar General Insurance Limited
company for Q2 and H1
fi4 let me give you a brief overview of
the industry Trends and developments
that we have witnessed in the past few
months po this our CFO Mr gopal
balachandran will share the financial
performance of the company for the
quarter and the half year ended
September 30
2023 the global economy is experiencing
experiencing a loss of momentum however
the Indian economy is gaining strength
led by domestic drivers such as private
consumption and fixed assip Investments
by public sector
capex the Southwest Monsoon rainfall
recovered during September however it
ended below the long period average the
manufacturing and services pmis and
other high frequency indicators
exhibited a robust expansion during this
quarter on the demand front Urban
consumption is buyant while rural demand
is showing some signs of Revival however
the current geopolitical conditions and
higher interest rates in the advanced
economies can impact Global and domestic
economic growth negatively and we have
to Be watchful of the same for the
quarter as per data published by CM the
new Private Car Sales continue to
deliver robust growth year on year the
two wheer sales registered moderate
growth for the quarter and in terms of
volume Still Remains below the pre
pandemic limits the commercial vehicle
growth was driven by growth in infra and
other core sectors health insurance
contined to deliver rer growth growth
remaining the largest contributor to
overall growth the commercial segment
witnessed growth in line with the
current market Market environment we
remain optimistic that the industry will
continue to grow given the favorable
macros regulatory changes low
penetration and relatively positive
consumer
sentiment speaking of the performance
The General insurance industry delivered
a gdpi growth of 14.9% for the first
half of this year over the first half of
last year excluding the crop insurance
growth is at 18% for the same period
overall the underwriting performance
worsen with a combined ratio of the
industry at
113.24 for q1 fi4 as against 11.4 for q1
fi23 for motor business while the combin
ratio continues to remain elevated the
combine ratio for the industry improved
to
12.1% from q1 2024 as against 124.5 for
q1
2023 moving to the business numbers for
us in Q2 F5 2024 the company grew at
17.4% as compared to the industry growth
of 12
12.5% in terms of growth of key segments
during the quarter Property and Casualty
line of business grew at 17.2% which was
higher than the industry growth of
8.6% further during the quarter we acced
market share across all segments such as
fire Marine engineering and
liability in motor our growth for the
quarter was 10.9% as against the
industry growth of
13.9% the growth in motor segment was
aided by robust growth of 27.6% in the
new Private Car segment the private car
mix stands at 51.8% for the for this
quarter while the competitive intens in
the motor segment remained elevated we
continue our focus of developing a
quality portfolio based on granular data
we continue to rebalance our portfolio
resulting in commercial vehicle mix at
22.1% and two wheer mix at 26.1% for
Quarter Two of this
year we also continue to hardness our
digital capabilities in building claims
efficiency in motor in Q2 24 through our
preferred partner Network PPN Network we
were able to service 63% of our non OEM
claims up from 44% in Q2 of
2023 the health segment continued to be
the fastest growing segment for the
industry during this quarter we grew at
20.3% as a result of our continued
investment in retail Health distribution
we have grown in line with the industry
at
18.7% this was driven by growth in
business SCE to the retail health agency
vertical of
21.7% I would Al like to share that our
onstop solution for all insurance and
wellness needs I take care app has surp
surpassed 6.9 million uh user download
till date the incremental download for
the quarter was 1.3 million for Q2 of
f24 the premium Source through I take
care app contributed to
88457 million to the overall gdpa
reflecting a 3.5 times increase year on
year we have been updating you about our
digital business initiatives like
digital wand and I take care which we've
been driving in an agile manner we are
now scaling these agile models to
business lines across the company
completely R redefining the ways of
working and the business processes
coupled with the transformation of the
core system we expect this to be a key
driver for a future growth as a
digitally impart insurance
company as you are all you may be aware
I have decided to pursue an overseas
opportunity after spending over 14.5
years with ICA Lombard it has been a
wonderful Journey for me and I'm
grateful for the collective support of
all our stakeholders our employees
customers Channel Partners analysts and
shareholders we have made large stdes in
the industry and made I a much loved
brand brand as India's largest private
sector GI player I take this opportunity
to thank all of you for your support and
hope you will extend the same support as
I pass on the beton to my dear colleague
sanjie
manri sanjie has been with the ICC group
for over 20 years sanjiv has played a St
Stellar role in terms of his achievement
within the company he spearheaded the
retail division as an executive director
where he was leading distribution of
products across agency Bank Insurance
direct and Alternate channels he was
also in charge of the strategy products
pricing marketing and corporate
communication verticals at IC Lombard
I'm convinced that ICC Lombard will
continue to be a strong force of
positive change in the industry under
his leadership over to you s thank you
Bara your leadership is an inspiration
for all of us and the St record over the
last 15 years has left an indeliberate
impact on the organization and the
industry at large we are excited for you
and the opportunities that lie ahead and
wish you the very best I'm keenly
looking forward to taking the journey
ahead and we rely heavily on the support
of all our stakeholders these are
interesting times for the G industry and
we very well positioned to capitalize on
this I look forward to meeting and
interacting with each one of you
personally we will continue to remain
focused on our overall philosophy of
balancing growth and
profitability I will now request gopal
to take you through the financial
numbers for the Recently concluded
quarter and half year
thanks to each one I now a brief
overview of the financial performance of
the recently concluded quarter and half
year we have uploaded the result
presentation on our website you can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers the gr direct
premium income of the company was at R
24.72 billion in H1 fi2 24 at against is
10 5.55 billion in H1 f23 a growth of
18.2% as against industry growth of
14.9% excluding crop GDP of the company
was at
17.6% which was in line with industry
growth of 18% in quarter to
f524 gdpi was at 6.86 billion in Q2 as
against 51.85 billion rupees in Q2 fi23
a growth of 17.4% this growth was higher
than the industry growth of
12.5% our GDP growth during the quarter
was primarily driven by growth in the
preferred segments the overall gdpi of
our Property and Casualty segment grew
by 17.2% at 14.76 billion rupees in
quarter to f24 as against R 12.59
billion in quarter to
fi23 on the retail side of the business
GDP of the motor segment was at rupes
2.38 billion in quarter to fi 24 as
against 1928 billion in Q2 fi23
registering a growth of
10.9% the advaned numbers was at rupes
32.892880
billion in Q2 fi23 registering a growth
of
20.3% our agents which included the
point of sale distribution count was at
461 as on September 303 2023 up from
around
17,49 as on June 30 2023 GDP of the
retail Health segment grew by
19% Group Health segment that's a
corporate employer employee segment grew
by 20.6% during the quarter the bank
insurance and kg group grew at 24.3%
this quarter during the quarter of
business source through our digital one
team grew by
26.7% overall our digital Focus has
enabled us to increase our digital
revenues which includes the IL take care
app business to rupees 3.66 billion
which accounts for 6% of our overall
gdpi for the
quarter Rec resultantly the combined
ratio was 103.7 for H1 FY 24 as against
10 14.6% for H1 FY 23 excluding the
impact of cat losses of r83 billion in
H1 fi 24 and rupes 28 billion in H1 fi23
the combined ratio was 10 12.7% and 104
4.2% respectively combined ratio was
103.9 in quarter 2 f24 as against 10
15.1% in quarter to fi23 excluding the
impact of C lesses of r48 billion in Q2
fi 24 and r28 billion in Q2 fi23 the
combined ratio was 10.8% and 10 14.3%
respectively our investment assets Rose
to rupes 43.122762
.05 billion as at June 30 2023 our
investment leverage net of borrowings
was 4.07 times as at September 30 2023
as againsted 4.16 times as at June 30
2023 investment income was at rupes 1.59
billion in h124 as against
13.94% 7.39 billion in Q2 fi23 our
capital gain net of empowerment on
investment assets stood at R 2.87
billion in H1 fi 24 as compared to rupes
1.43 billion in H1
fi23 capital gains net of impairment or
investment assets stood at R 1.65
billion in Q2 fi4 as compared to rupes
1.11 billion in Q2 fi23 our profit
before tax grew by 19.4% Ates 12.84
billion in H1 f24 as against R 10.75
billion in H1 fi23 whereas CBT grew by
25.3% at 7.64 billion in Q2 f524 as
against R 6.10 billion in Q2 fi23
consequently profit after tax grew by 3%
at R 9.68 billion H1 f24 as against 9.4
billion in Hy H1 f23 F degw by 2.2% at R
5 5.77 billion in Q2 fi4 from rupes 5.91
billion in Q2
fi23 op request has been initiated if
you'd like to cancel this request please
press St Z again 2% in H1
f24
and 24.8% in Q2 FY
24 return on average Equity was 18% in
H1
fi4
fi23 the Roe for quarter to f24 was
21.1% as against 24.5% in quarter to
fi23 solcy ratio was at 2.59 times as at
September 13th 2023 as against 2.53
times as at June 30 2023 continued to be
higher than the regulatory minimum
requirement of 1.5 times the board of
directors of the company has declared
interim dividend of rupees 5 per share
for H1 f524 as against rupes 4.5 per
share for H1
fi23 as I conclude I would like to
reiterate we continue to stay focused on
driving profitable growth sustainable
value creation and safeguarding the
interest of policy holders at all times
I would like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
now be happy to take any specific
questions that you have thank you thank
you very much we will now begin the
question and answer session anyone who
wishes to ask a question may press star
and one on their Touchstone telephone
if you wish to withdraw yourself from
the question Q you may press star and
two participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question ladies
and gentlemen we will wait for a moment
while the question Q
assembles our first question is from the
line of a Singh from MK Global please go
ahead yeah hi good evening uh thanks for
the opportunity uh best wishes to you
Vargo for your future endeavors and
congratulations to Sanju on his new role
uh uh good set of performance a couple
of questions uh first one uh I mean on
your motor side of course uh you
commented about the competitive
intensity uh but whatever I see
incrementally in your quarter two
overall motor profitability seems to be
quite good for you yet you remain sort
of very very guarded with the motor I
mean so why such I would say the guarded
approach even when profitability seems
to be suggesting that okay things are
better than what they were a few
quarters back so that is on your entire
strategy around motor because even in
motor CV you started to sort of uh take
a bit of more business but again there
you it seems that okay you have sort of
TR to slow down so on overall motor I
would like to understand the philosophy
and on the same point now I guess if I
understand the regulation correctly now
even motor TP technically a commission
is sort of a possible because I mean the
business line wise commission caps are
gone so what is sort of practices you
are witnessing in the market as far as
motor is concerned so that's on motor
and on health uh I of course I see that
okay uh the uh results are coming from
your focus on agency and that sort of
leading to sort of a grow in retail yet
if I see because you are growing uh
strongly in the group both on the banker
side as well as the employer employee uh
your mix is Shifting again more towards
uh group I mean of course the Bankai is
largely retail I understand yet I'm
think that on your individual side uh I
mean is that growth still a bit you are
calibrated or why I mean uh because on
the group employers employees idy that
and the price hike is now behind so it
would be largely kind of a volum l
growth so that growth is a strong Bank
growth is strong is I mean so on the
pure P retail why sort of a bit of
slower as for your own experience the
two question thank
you uh thanks and maybe sanj can answer
the
question yeah sure so
thanks clearly from a motor perspective
as you rightly said there are enough and
more Tails available at the industry
level and we are well set to
capitalized uh in the way in your
question itself I see the answer that we
are able to drive it profitably because
we have kept ourselves cated and we've
also always maintained that we will move
where we see an opportunity in terms of
profit pool uh if you look at our own
configuration of motor portfolio overall
you will see that the CV portfolio has
marginally gone down in terms of a
contribution in HED fund of 23.4 it
moved to
21.6 and we have growth on private car
and two wheer as a company uh if you ask
me in terms of the view the way we
expect ourselves uh we we would continue
to exert what is required uh but if we
see intensity which is uh in our mind
not working out overall we will probably
be attacked CES in terms of driving it
so overall our plan of uh being
competitive and being in this play
because this is where a key distribution
is we will continue to exert ourselves
as a team on the health part which you
spoke about in terms of growth coming
primly from Group Health rather than
retail uh if you see our investment
largely has been on the retail side and
there you'll see a Delta over industry
growth of 2% Group Health always
maintained that we going strategically
if we see that we are able to uh see
some sanity in terms of pricing we going
deep that's what we did in quarter one
but in Quarter Two If you see we have
grown rather subdued res is the market
uh that plan per se for us as a company
uh will not change but trajectory on the
retail side is far more permanent and
you will see it doing much better
there's a marginal Improvement in market
share but I would not like to read too
much into that because over a period of
time we would do much better and we
continue to stay invested as far as
health agency is
concerned yeah thank you and that
question regarding uh you know current
practices around Commissions in motor
because I mean technically now I mean
one can pay commissions on motor TP as
well so what sort of a market I mean
post of you know basically the
commission caps are going to cap what
kind of a market practices you are
seeing as far as the pay offs are
concerned so ainash clearly we spoke
about the industry level numbers on
motor and we see a marginal Improvement
in the overall combined ratio from 124
is moved to 120 uh Frankly Speaking
there's not too much you can read in
those numbers as far as this this point
of time even on expense of management
while it has come in you see almost 50%
of the company being more than the limit
which is there which is stated uh have
we seen uh overall rationality
prevailing across Frankly Speaking the
industry itself is adjusting adjusting
to it at this point of time and over a
period of time I do believe that you
will see far more rationalization than
what's happened now and we we do expect
SCH to come in by quarter three or
quarter 4 in overall from an overall
perspective okay thank you thank you
thank you our next question is from the
line of sha Shivani from clsa please go
ahead yes uh thank you for the
opportunity and congratulation on a good
set of numbers uh so sir on the coming
back on the motor book I wanted some
more understanding on uh the loss ratio
Improvement that has happened in 1 H
versus 1q uh I know you don't want us to
look at on look at loss ratios on
quarterly basis but if uh even even the
1ed numbers look quite good so that
would be one question uh second is on
the uh monthly performance so uh while I
understand your monthly performances do
vary but if you can give us some color
in uh understanding what specifically
happened in probably August and
September because still July you guys
were had a very strong run rate of about
20% so uh any color now around what
happened and uh any growth Outlook that
you can uh give and so so one more
question third question from probably
you've launched a new product with IC
pro life the health and protection
product management mentioned in the
conference call yesterday so if you can
give us some understanding of the
economics of such a product you know uh
premiums uh the way uh partnership with
IC Pro works out I'm assuming this will
get sold on the IC Bank platform so some
color on
that so sh uh I think on the first one I
think if you look at uh on the loss
ratios for motor
um I think you're right I think we keep
saying that you should never look at
numbers over quarters or even let's say
even on a financial year basis because
some of these lines will obviously kind
of start to exhibit U outcomes over a
relatively longer period of time
particularly in the context of motor
third party uh having said that I think
when you look at even for let's say the
half year uh on motor OD specifically in
general what we have talked about is the
portfolio loss ratio should kind of
range between the 65 to 70% kind of
threshold on motor own damage uh for the
half year I think that number is at
let's say 65% or thereabout but that's
the range at which you would possibly
see depending on what kind of a business
mix that we write in terms of whether we
are able to relatively pick pick up a
higher proportion of new or let's say
relatively what kind of proportion are
we able to write in the context of the
older portfolio so that's broadly the
range at which we will be able to
operate at within quarters obviously the
loss ratios will undergo a CH change but
that's the range that we are comfortable
with in so far as uh the own damage book
is concerned on third party again the
point is to the same I think while for
the quarter you would have again seen
the numberers slightly better or let's
say even on a half yearly basis I think
number stands at about 66% but these are
experiences that one should logically
again look at uh over relatively longer
periods uh and also to the fact that
depending on what kind of a mix of
business that we write in terms of
Private Car two- wheer and CV and that's
something that we keep calibrating from
time to time corresponding to which you
could possibly see a change in the loss
ratio uh experience uh but otherwise
there's nothing specific to call out in
the context of let's say uh the quarter
two numbers having said that I think
what we also keep doing is given the
fact that from a reserving perspective
generally we have tried to be prudent at
all points of time that philosophy still
continues to remain the same uh even as
we write whichever portfolio of the book
but over a period of time as you would
have seen some of our experiences have
actually started to turn out to be much
much positive and let's say what our
initial estimates have been so that will
obviously get calibrated from time to
time but otherwise in so far as overall
portfolio is concerned it's purely a
function of what kind of mixers mix of
business that that we able to write just
to add to a point that gopal made is
that the way we look at businesses on a
combined basis not just loss ratio and
overall you should study your numbers on
a combined perspective certain
businesses May have higher expenses uh
you know lower loss isue and byy versa
so as a as a team we look at overall
combined as a as a
objetive for the combo product that got
ra yes we very excited we have taken the
term and the uh CHR product of ours and
given combined offering to our customers
through our agency channel uh if you
look at it crew has a very decent agency
practice and very decent Bank Insurance
practice and there was uh a gap which
needed to be filled we have created this
product line to you know leverage on
each other's distribution and as for the
regulatory environment that is there
it's something which is a very feasible
option we have gone ahead and done this
uh partnership with them and we expect
this product to probably ramp up in time
to come uh to be very honest our agents
will require a bit of a training and
process it will come with a lag over a
period of time but but that being said
we really excited with this partnership
that we have done with them to drive uh
the combo product in the market which in
many ways is first of its kind and last
question sha on the monthly performance
numbers again I think that's purely a
function of uh what kind of businesses
do we write between periods uh as we had
explained even in the earlier call our
business do tend to have a bit of C
legality across businesses uh so for
example in quarter one you will
obviously see a relatively higher
proportion of some of the commercial
lines being underwritten in Quarter Two
we do see businesses booked particularly
in the context of crop now that could
get booked in a in a particular month
and therefore to that extent you may
possibly see variations in growth
percentages uh when you look at it
relatively on a month on Monon basis but
here again as we keep saying I think a
better way to look at given the
cyclicality of the business that we get
get to see and maybe for example quarter
three you will see a lot more business
largely driven through let's say some of
the retail growth uh so again you may
see let's say month- on month changes
between segments of businesses U but
however when you look at it on a full
year basis I think in line with what we
have spoken uh largely looking at way
looking at the way how how things are
positively shaping up for us uh we
should definitely look at ending the
year within that high percentage growth
that we have talked about and uh in
general I mean depending on what Sanji
also mentioned uh on the experence of
management side I think if things starts
to get uh improved much better from an
industry perspective then the relative
outperformance that we have talked about
of 100 200 basis point over and above
the market growth rate that's something
that we still believe we will be able to
achieve got it sir thank you this
answers my question thank
you thank
you our next question is from the line
of nides from invest Tech please go
ahead uh thanks for the opportunity uh
uh what is the share of OEM and non OEM
buiness in the motor and how it has been
trending over last two to three
years overall if you see in our split in
terms of the M we speaking about we will
almost have 70% of a business coming
from the OEM business and the rest be
coming through other channels with the
agency and Bank
Insurance sure I think last year we
articulated Our intention to move
towards to increase the share of non OEM
by focusing on high loss ratio low low
expense ratio uh business uh so how is
the progress on that has a share of non
OEM going up so uh overall if you see
again uh uh incrementally yes we intend
exercising ourselves more on the agency
side but uh the manner in which a motor
book has got created uh there's a fair
amount of contribution and if you see an
opportunity there it's not one for the
other we'll continue to invest
extensively on the agency business side
but that being said
where we have been working for years and
build a franchise we will continue to
drive that uh so we need to look at both
of both of these in a in a standalone
there there are times that o
contribution can go really up I mean I
mean there's a season coming in quarter
3 obviously you will find again om you
know uh probably showing a larger
percentage but that being said agency
business should continue to do well but
relatively to put percentage pool would
be a very uh difficult option it's not
one for the other so NES just to add to
supplement what San said I think
strategically and philosophically while
we are investing there will be times
when OEM will again come back up right
so if new vehicle sales increase as has
happened as we said in the opening
remarks uh I think the share of new
vehicle sales has been very positive for
us and those are profitable pools so
when we see those opportunities we want
to guard
them sure understood understood secondly
I noticed that there is some change in
the Senior Management personnel
uh structure uh so if you can explain
what is the rational for that and what
is this Emerging Market group uh if you
can share some details on that Emerging
Market group so effectively it's a very
minor not a significant CH but we have
an experienced resource which has joined
in and he's an expert in terms of
driving the emerging market so we have P
them in to report into Alo which
otherwise had a multiple reporting so we
want to use the benefit of his presence
in the
system and Emerging Market group is a is
a commercial l or IM
Market operates across channels and
business lines basically this is the you
know B rather than the top cities right
so this is where if you remember last
year we had done a little bit of you
know structuring change
where was looking after after wholesale
business was given specific Focus given
charge of that that market with specific
focus and we are investing and we are
growing that business uh so typically
let's say the top 40 cities would be not
there but thereafter it would be
considered to be
emerging sure sure thank you that's it
from my side thank you thank
you ladies and gentlemen in order to
ensure that the management is able to
address questions from all participants
in the conference please limit your
questions to one or two for participant
should you have a followup question we
would request you to rejoin the queue
thank you uh next question is from the
line of sanet G from Evis Park please go
ahead yeah uh thank you thank you for
the
opportunity my first question is that
whether whether you want to preone your
guidance of
102.5 to be achieved because because X
of c c process if I see you are almost
there uh uh what what we have thought we
will achieve by exit of fi25 so so just
wanted to understand whether whether uh
given given the underwriting environment
you believe that could happen little
quicker than expected that's Point
number one and and second within within
the uh this 102.5 or combined ratio
Improvement mean the some some vage was
expected to come from the Opex part but
despite U Opex compared to last year
still still has been higher or or in man
also it's higher so I just wanted to
understand that eom is overall dragging
the Opex low higher or increasing the
Opex on the higher side or or you
believe sanity will come and um will
expense ratios will improve for the
sector
as s cut a bit of slack to the team
right I you just you're delivering
better than expected numbers and that's
what we want to continue to do uh no
change in guidance as you know the
market is still very competitive we
talked about where the combined issue
for the industry is in terms of motor
share motor segment uh but clearly I
think over the last one year the team
has done a brilliant job in terms of uh
uh you know significantly calibrating uh
the business as also building a lot of
capability on the cost side both on the
claims and and expense side uh so I
think you know we the team is doing
really well but there's no need to
change guidance as we see it at this
point in time on the cost side I'll ask
gopal to answer yeah so I think San we
will we will still continue to maintain
what we have been kind up talking about
which is uh I think the businesses has
always have to be looked at as what Baro
also just mentioned in response to
earlier one which is we always look at
the businesses from an overall combined
perspective uh because different
businesses would obviously have a mix of
let's say loss experience and let say
the expense ratios as well uh just to
kind of uh look at the overall expense
of management specifically to answer
your point uh first half of last year
our expense of management was a
27.3 relative to that if you look at our
first half of this year we are at about
26.9 uh so hence to that extent even
from an e perspective we have actually
seen a marginal Improvement in line with
what we definitely wanted to kind of
drive it towards and this is despite the
fact that we continue to make our
investments in those areas of building
Distribution on health agency technology
some of the core transformation project
that we talked about I think clearly we
would want to continue to make those
Investments and hence to that extent you
may not suddenly see a big shift
happening in so far as specifically in
the context of the expense ratio numbers
are concerned we will obviously Drive uh
a a positive change but having said that
I think we will directionally be more
Guided by the other objective that we
are specifically spelled out which got
rated as we speak which is the combined
ratio objective of 102% is something
that we want to achieve by the end of
next year so that's something that we
want to clearly drive and as I said
purely uh the breakdown of expense is
function of loss and
expens got it got
it just last two questions one question
which is one data keeping typical loss
ratio of retail health and Group Health
uh that that if you can share and second
just just wanted to understand this I
take care app 6% of GW is is a big big
achievement so so how do you see this to
be contributing and and and if you can
give a color how much is mix driven by
motor and heal in in I Tech
K so so the number of 6% is the digital
contribution uh s the second Point
second part of your question uh so
therefore to that action that also
includes let's say the business that we
Source through I take care app and as we
have been talking about I think
consistently whether you look at it on a
year- on-ear basis obviously there is a
multiplier increase in so far as the
premium that we are sourcing through I
take care is concerned roughly about 3.7
times increase that we have seen uh but
even when you look at it on a sequential
basis I think we have been able to kind
of grow the contribution coming in
through that particular uh particular
app so we are very very excited with the
way how things are getting played out
and uh equally we are getting to see a
lot more uh product per customer in so
far as the use of the app is concerned
and that will continue to drive both
volumes as well as let's say value of
premium in so far as a digital
contribution is concerned uh to your
first point in so far as the breakdown
of the loss ratios are concerned I think
for Quarter Two uh the breakdown of the
overall health loss ratios into
corporate health and Retail Indemnity
corporate Health loss ratios are at
about 102% and the retail Health inity
loss ratios are
66.6% now this number I think when when
the numbers that we gave out for quarter
one last year corporate Health was about
92.6 and the retail Health inity numbers
were 64.2 now obviously these numbers
have to be looked at in the context of
how do we see some of the loss
insurances play out and particularly in
Water 2 we do the get to see a slight
increase in loss incidents primarily
because typically it's a monsoon season
and we get to see a lot more increase in
uh health related ailments that we get
to see and this is not specifically only
for this particular quarter 2 even
otherwise when you look at it even for
the last year for example clearly we had
seen an increase in the loss ratios
playing out between let's say a quarter
two versus a quarter one so hence in
that sense I think we are pretty much
okay with the way how the loss
experiences is playing out and as we had
indicated in so far as the portfolio
growth is concerned I think it is coming
at a price at which we are comfortable
with and uh in the subsequent quarters
we should start seeing some of these
loss ratios getting normalized
particularly in the context of lowering
down of loss insurances that we see in
Q3 and Q4 just to supplement what gopal
said you know and we've talked about
this in the past the entire thought
process uh and the and the approach
behind I take care was uh consumer
engagement right engaging with our
customers be it you know uh the employer
employee segment where the individual is
a potential retail customer or a retail
customer b2c customer who comes on board
and uh and the approach that we are
taking is that as we have more engaged
customers they will renew better you
will have costal opportunities and
hopefully the relationship will be more
sticky so principally for us whatever
business we get as long as it's viable
we are not driving motor numbers or
health numbers there it's a customer
engagement app and uh and and as an
organization we don't want to split that
number at this point in time to say okay
this is my motor number this is my
health number because it might drive us
in a manner which is not customer
Centric uh so uh so as an organization
we've been giving the numbers in terms
of number of app downloads the total
volume of crale and upsale business that
we are doing which is something that we
continue
to thank you sorry to interrupt Mr sanit
GA may we request that you return to the
question cu for followup questions as
there are several participants waiting
for their turn thank you
sir our next question is from the line
of SW mukarji from bnk Securities please
go
ahead hi sir thank you for the
opportunity and congrats on good set of
numbers so I'll again come back to you
know the motor loss ratios so uh I
understand that what you have
articulated in terms of uh your
experience and maybe some relases that I
coming uh but just you know for a view
of how the loss ratios are going to pan
out I mean say for in mot TP uh your
loss ratios have been little bit
fluctuating over quarters uh right now
that there has been a bit of a
Improvement going ahead if you can give
some color from the full year how we
should think about this number where it
can sustain same for OD given that you
you are picking up on growth on the only
business and particular private vehicle
in the mix how confident would you be in
kind of maintaining this kind of loss
ratio so that is the first one and uh
secondly uh in terms of the investment
income I just wanted to understand the
yield that you have shown realized
return
is fairly strong I think slightly higher
than what we have done in the past so is
there certain uh you know tactical bets
that have you know that have worked out
which might not play out in the coming
for us so and what kind of e we can
think about for the you know going ahead
on a normalized basis yeah so SP on the
first one I think uh which is what I
kind of responded uh to the earlier one
uh and one had kind of talked about the
range at which we would be comfortable
so one I think when we look at motor as
a line of business we obviously look at
it again more from a combined
perspective which will be a combination
of both the loss experience and let's
say the expense ratios and as what we
just discussed again it will depend on
what proportion of new business that we
write because new typically comes with a
relatively better loss experience and
correspondingly let's say the expense
ratios could slightly stay elevated and
correspondingly let's say the older
portfolios as we just discussed
typically comes with a slightly high LR
and let's say a relatively lower cost of
distribution so honestly that will be a
interplay that one one would get to see
in so far as writing this book is
concerned but having said that I think
the range at which one would be
comfortable to operate in the context of
motor own damage is what I kind of
responded earlier which is in the range
of between 65 to 70% depending on what
kind of a business mix that we write in
in in respect of proportion of uh uh new
or let's say is the relatively older
portfolio on third party again pretty
much we have kind of talked about as
what I responded obviously we should
again not look at these numbers uh
particularly for quarters or let's say
even on halfly basis uh you have to look
at the numbers over relatively longer
period uh so there again it will be a
function of what uh kind of loss
experiences that one sees but broadly I
would say that one could see the third
party loss ratios again kind of hovering
around what you see on a full year basis
that would be largely representative of
the range range at which we would get to
see the loss ratio play out so that's
the response uh to your first one uh to
your second one on the overall uh
investment book uh I think uh in fact in
the past quarters people have been
asking us why have we not seen let's say
so much of an increase in the overall uh
interest income of the portfolio uh now
if you recollect I think what we
generally do is uh depending on the
market opportunity that one sees is how
we place our overall portfolio at and
for example we tend to kind of in this
High interestate environment we
obviously want to capitalize the
opportunity that one sees and so far as
uh approval to the book is is concerned
and which is why our overall uh duration
of the book in fact stands at about 5.23
years this number if I remember it
correctly uh at the end of the at the
beginning of the year uh was at about
4.99 years so obviously we have gone a
bit long and we have kind of rightly
positioned the portfolio in order to
capitalize as I said the increased uh uh
interest rate that one sees in the
market so hence to that extent we will
obviously get to see this kind of play
out even as we kind of head into the
subsequent quarters what is it that you
will not necessarily see playing out
over the subsequent period is purely a
function of the extent of capital gains
that one sees in the market that's
purely driven by let's say the market
opportunity that one sees and even in
the past we have talked about it uh
between quarters you can always see
fluctuations in the breakup of the
overall investment income uh depending
on how Market plays out is what you will
be able to see some kind of gain playing
out so so hence to answer your point I
think the way we are positioned the
portfolio is what is helping us in terms
of capitalizing the uh increased uh uh
interest
income and just to just to supplement
the point that gopal made uh this is
we've been talking about this that our
car yield will increase and gopal's
given this number if you also look at
the split of the unrealized gains the
unrealized gain the equity book has
increased uh at the end of this quarter
uh obviously on the dead side and the
bond side has come down because interest
rates have gone gone up but that is not
not something that we worried about
because these are all uh calls that
we've taken to stay long in uh in the
Deb Market that's how I ERS
increase understood sir yeah but thank
you so much and all the best thanks
thanks
much thank you our next question is from
the line of Rishi junjun Wala from iifl
institutional equities please go
ahead yeah thanks for the opportunity
just a couple of questions uh uh firstly
you know the September month would have
seen the first 5year anniversary of the
two-wheeler long-term TP um so how has
the experience been in terms of renewal
it is it you know given that 5 years of
TP means that the renewals have pretty
much down to zero and and as a result uh
you know if you can give some color in
terms of what would you know that amount
of prium for September month b as
proportion of overall motor
TP so uh uh uh thanks you see uh clearly
yes this was the first month uh
overarchingly if you ask me over
industry level there's a good reason why
I think Supreme Court get the verdict in
terms of having long-term this the
retention rates continue to be
relatively on the lower side I would not
split enough of the amount but retention
level that we are seeing as a team right
now is around 15 to 20% uh the
development of this will happen over you
know submission of probably a water in
terms of what are the two numbers
because we'll have to pursue this uh uh
with our own customers and see where we
end up losing it but it's but it's
something as a pool that we very keen so
we're using all possible analytics to
see if we can further sharpen our X and
see that uh we can dite these numbers uh
even if it's only TP we'll be more than
happy to write this
pool understood and the second is uh
just on the total payouts to the
distribution
uh channels um you know some of our life
insurance Speers have talked about um
you know industrywide increase in
payouts uh to the distribution channels
um how has it behaved uh for us uh in
the the key banka partner Channel as
well as outside of that uh in terms of
the total payout I understand there was
you know uh you know categorization or
reclassification but just in terms of
payout has there been uh demand for
increase in payouts for us and have you
seen any kind of anomalies in the
industry otherwise so uh overall if you
see for us as a company expense of
management has stayed within the range
uh and in fact it's come down uh from a
27.3 to 26.9 uh so Frankly Speaking uh
there is no accelerative increase but in
certain Pockets where we have seen a bit
of an acceleration you will see that
dynamically we will go again to what our
basic thesis has been uh we will change
where we can get viable business in
terms of acquiring it uh in a way to
some extent you can see our motor market
share also is reflecting that we had a
calibrated growth uh to maintain
profitability over just market share
growth so you can read in terms of
what's happening over AR but overall
will seem to be in control uh at this
point of
time
okay thank you so
much thank you our next question is from
the line of PR Jen from moal please go
ahead Mr PR Jen your line has been
unmuted you can
go hi congratulations great of numbers
uh firstly uh you know I just miss the
agency count number can you just repeat
it's about 1 lak 122,000 which includes
the agency that includes the point of
sale distribution as well so this was it
is 1 lak 122,000 this number at the end
of uh uh earlier period was about 1 lak
13,000 okay okay and just on the prev
question sorry to interrupt Jen may we
request you to use your answer please as
your audio is M sir thank you is this
better hello hello your voice is
slightly more feeble uh PR we can't hear
you
clearly come back in the cas sorry thank
sir our next question is from the line
of mukar L from noama wealth management
please go
ahead hi uh good evening and
congratulations on a good set of numbers
couple of questions uh one we seeing a
good increase in the crop business uh
that you're doing this year what is the
philosophy uh behind that uh I remember
in the past you wanted to avoid that
business and u i I also know that you
got this business again from
bti uh so is that only those States or
are you also growing some of the other
states uh so that's that's one second uh
again I'm just going back to the
guidance of
102% given that your performance is
quite strong and you know in first half
itself you are at
102.7 so uh are you being a little bit
too
conservative over
here um and finally um you know most of
the industry is uh ahead sorry is not
meeting the uh e uh Norms right now um
you know so what regulatory action can
we expect and and what would you say uh
by when uh will the regulator start
looking at this and implementing
this thanks M let me answer it in the
same sequence one on crop there is no
change in philosophy as gopal had
explained that I think sanj explained
that there are certain months where you
book a premium it just shows up in that
quarter uh in aggregate our share of
crop business which we have guided the
market was to be would be around 5% of
total business for the annual business
not on a quarterly basis and I think
we'll stay at at that kind of range we
are not significantly growing our crop
book uh in spite of the fact that we
believe some players in the market are
trying to do that because of the
advantage that they get get on E but
philosophically you don't believe that's
the right strategy right approach so we
are not doing that uh uh there was some
amount of booking in the K season
because most of the business for us is
in the K Market C period so it's it's a
bit higher in this quarter that's about
all secondly most of the propop that you
got is in the 18810 model uh so it's a
reasonably well- contained uh business
and our experience in the last couple of
years has been very reasonably positive
on the approach that we
had in terms of your question on
uh combine ra coming to question on
combin add uh you know whether we are
being conservative that's your call you
you take your own views about whether we
being combined conservative I think as I
said the guidance should remain the same
if you can outperform all of you should
be happy uh third in terms of the
regulatory action uh look it's not for
us to talk about what the regulator will
do uh but uh at least we uh hope and we
think that this time the regulator is
very serious about this uh at the same
time this is not about a quar numbered
that they're monitoring they will monit
theyve given a B for a company on annual
basis and my my my sense is that the end
of the year they look at who's improved
and who's not improved and who's gone
beyond
30% uh so I think it would be wise for
most companies which are already running
it higher than that number I think it
would be wise for them to bring it under
control but as I said it's not for us to
talk about what the regulator will do
that's a question that uh in a sense you
time will give us the answer and we'll
see what the regulator does thanks just
a follow up on this sir are we seeing uh
heightened competitive intensity in the
group health segment also uh to sort of
meet the UN Norms I think goal answered
that and you know in the first quarter
we saw the market on goal to be better
and we had a much higher share uh this
quarter we've seen some amount of uh uh
aggression and in fact we've seen some
otherwise sensible companies buy very
large chunky groupal businesses our
senses it's probably to manage the
extensive management but at the end of
the day business is not just about
extensive management business is about
combin right so you to do it in a manner
which is sensible so uh We'll Be
watchful uh and we'll see what what
happens but overall at this point in
time we are quite comfortable with the
group health business that we
writing got uh thank you and all the
best thank you our next question is from
the line of ntin Chaat from kotak
institutional equities please go ahead
uh thanks for taking my question uh just
a small one uh you know when I look at
the monthly uh you know monthly figures
for motor PP business I was just curious
that uh you know did you do any
transaction in the last month you know
just as something that we had done
probably in the Feb or March month last
year
no n they've not done any
transactions perfect thanks that answers
my question thank
you thank
you our next question is from the line
of super team data from Ambit Capital
please go
ahead thanks for the
opportunity uh just wanted to understand
a few things so one the 0.48 billion of
you know natat la
which lines of business are those
attributed
to it's been largely so this water has
been largely let's say relatively retail
so we have had a higher proportion of
losses coming in from the motor line of
business but equally we have also had
some amount of claims coming in on the
property side unlike water one where
relatively the uh losses of roughly
about 35 crores which was the cat losses
in q1 that was largely property heav
as compared to
motor got it and uh within so if I
adjust for that ncat losses there in the
motor OD line then that would result in
the loss ratio being lower than 60% is
that a correct assumption and then my
followup question to that is you know
how sustainable is this loss ratio going
forward uh so uh I had kind of already
responded to that but just to kind of
rate rate uh again we will keep saying
this and you will get to hear us from
time and again you should never look at
quarterly numbers uh and largely it is
better to kind of look at numbers more
on a yearly basis U just to kind of rate
rate on motor own damage I think the
loss ratio depending on the kind of mix
of business that we write in motor we
are comfortable at a loss ratio range
between 65 to 70% uh that's the range
depending on what kind of business mix
of business we write and on TP again
again it's better to kind of look at
more annual numbers uh which is largely
reflective of the loss ratio range that
one would be comfortable writing so
hence to that extent whether you adjust
it for qu to losses from cat in the loss
ratios but if you do that on a simple
basis then obviously yes the loss ratio
will definitely look better than what
the reported numbers are but having said
that I think the range at which we are
comfortable at is between 65 to uh 70%
and what equally we need to remember is
that U whatever be the amount of losses
I think we do have appropriate
reinsurance support such that uh if
there's a very large uh catet event
having an impact on the net that gets
appropriately protected through
necessary reinsurance
management got it and just one last
question so on the fire side there has
been a Slowdown in the second quarter so
just wanted to understand how much of
this is due to the iib burn rates being
removed
uh versus you know overall competition
or you know you wanting to not right
some kind of business so just understand
on that the experience is what we
discussed at the end in the first
quarter is the same which is that
roughly about 5 6% reduction from the
earlier R which is uh better than what
we had actually we had anticipated at
the beginning of the year we'll have to
see if this holds in terms of fire there
are you know maybe one or two large
policies that have got move from period
to you know you know and there some uh
you know policies you earlier booked in
this period which may have got Mo move
somewhere else so you should look at the
numbers with a longer period rather than
just a quarter the only thing just to
add to that I think having said that I
think we look at across segments on the
commercial lines I think we still
continue to outperform the market I
think we continue to accreate market
share uh in fire as a line of business
or whether you take any of the other
commercial lines we continue to outow
the
market s uh thank you that's very
helpful thank you thank you ladies and
gentlemen due to time constraint that
was the last question of our question
and answer session I would now like to
hand the conference over to Mr bav Das
Gupta for closing
com thank you thank you everyone uh I
think all of you have been great support
to uh to the company and me personally
and I really want to take this
opportunity to thank all of you for the
being a great analysts and and investors
in our company uh as I said earlier I'm
hoping that you'll continue to engage
with that as you have in the past and
Sanji wants to have the last
word no I think absolute pleasure and uh
really Keen to interact with each one of
you personally as in when your schedule
permits uh nothing much to add but
absolutely in agreement with bab that uh
we've had you know great and discussions
with all of you and that continues thank
you so much and let's meet up soon thank
you thank you thank you on behalf of
ICICI Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited that concludes this conference
thank you for joining us and you may now
disconnect your lines